本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：阿好  卫老哥  艾瑞卡  幸田实果子
-你被  -监视着
-You are being -Watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
翻译：宅女之后  灰灰是菇凉  天朝直属
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
时间轴：阿包  凭陵新月  兜兜兜爹   日语听写： 青椒
三级操作
■
特效&压制：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
名叫"根"
Name's root.
疑似雇凶  五人中弹
她是黑客  勒索犯  杀人凶手
She's a hacker, extortionist, murderer.
疑似雇凶  五人中弹
涉嫌雇凶谋杀的竞选经理身亡
首席执行官遇刺身亡
她黑进人脑就跟黑进电脑一样简单
She hacks human beings as easily as she hacks computers.
我并不想控制你的机器
I don't want to control your machine.
我只想要放它自由
I just want to set it free.
我已经放了
I already did.
机器给了我一个任务
The machine's given me a mission.
形势在演变
Things are evolving.
你说你是界面
You say you're an interface,
你的眼睛和耳朵是你的接口
Your eyes and your ears are your ports,
我们可以阻止
We can put a stop to that.
你当初听我的话就好了
I wish you'd listened.
那样硬盘就不会误入敌手
Then the drives would have never fallen into the wrong hands.
撒马利亚人备份代码
德西玛科技
Decima Technologies.
■
化名  格里尔  约翰
运营总监
德西玛科技
我的"撒马利亚人"
My Samaritan...
你注定将成就伟业
you are destined for great things.
车辆追踪
转狱
目的地  丹维尔监狱
乘客
3名警卫
8名囚犯
定位主体
面部识别系统
匹配度
菜鸟
New fish,
要点建议[龟头]不
You want a tip?
免了  谢了
No, thanks.
太可惜了  不仅是头  整个儿都给你噢
That's too bad, 'cause you're getting the whole thing.
去看看
Go check it out.
女士  喂
Ma'am, hello?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我没事  劳你费心
I'm fine. Thanks for asking.
下去看看  我们有麻烦了
Get out there. We've got a problem.
上啊  牛逼货
Go get 'em, biggie.
给他们点颜色看看
Show 'em what you got.
你  举起手来  趴在
You, hands in the air-- get down on the--aah!
瞧瞧瞧瞧
What have we here?
宝贝儿  给爷尝尝味儿吧
Hey, baby. I want a piece of that.
比利
Billy.
想离开这儿吗
Wanna get outta here?
来吧  小甜心
Come on, sugar.
不如把哥也带上
Why don't you take me with--
我也叫比利啊
My name's Billy too!
我们认识吗
So do we know each other?
好了  找到他了  然后呢
All right, I have him. What's next?
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
你是谁  喂
Who are you? Hello?
喂
Hello!
站错边了  我这只耳朵聋了
Wrong side. I'm deaf in that ear.
你会说德国口音吗
Can you do a German accent?
学着
Learn.
是的  多谢留意
Yes, thank you for noticing.
多谢你把我救出来
Look, thanks for busting me out and all,
可这到底是怎么回事
but what the hell is going on?
你这件事  比利
In your case, Billy,
我还没弄清楚
I haven't figured that out yet.
我只知道未来
All I know is that the fate of the future
岌岌可危
hangs in the balance,
这其中需要你这一角色
And you have some role to play.
刮胡子
Shave.
好吧  我倒不想埋怨
Yeah, I don't mean to complain,
不过我看我是命不久矣
but I'm probably gonna die soon.
裤子会有点长
The pants will be a bit long.
你要我偷什么
So what do you need me to boost?
你知道我是偷车贼  是吧
You do know I'm a car thief, right?
不知道  也不在乎
I don't know, don't care.
我的老大只给我必要的信息
My boss only gives me the information I need to do my job,
而且
And...
签名
现在必要的是你学会这个签名  要快
right now I need you to learn this signature, fast.
我需要
I'm gonna need a--
"茄子"
はい　チ`ズ
麻烦快点
急いでください。
这位是北山
That's Daizo.
我上个月从东京警察手里救出了他
I saved him from the Tokyo police last month.
之后他就一直跟着我了
He's been with me ever since.
好了吗
We good?
我被抓时你去哪儿了呢
Where were you when I got busted?
斯通牧场精神病院
Ranch Stone psychiatric facility.
■
模拟互动界面:  活动中
截击距离
米
到了
Here we are.
-哪儿  -不知道
- Where? - No idea.
谢谢
どうも。
甘特施密兹
国防部文职人员
国家计算机安全协会
我最喜欢你这样了
I love it when you do this.
不是说你  进去吧
Not you. Go inside now.
最高机密
施密兹博士
Dr. Schmitz?
施密兹博士  有你的包裹
Dr. Schmitz, got a package for you.
请出示证件并签名
I.D. and signature, please.
签名查实
你换发型了
Did you change your hair?
是的  多谢留意
Yes, thank you for noticing.
走吧  免得他到
We should go before he gets here.
谁
Who?
S03E16中被前任救  被里叔放  被根妹代宝宝收集的技术宅
パ`スのLれ家でケ`シ`に会ってください。
去[澳大利亚]佩斯的安全屋见凯西
回见
また会いましょう。
这到底是什么情况啊
So what was all this?
我的老大和我正在设法
My boss and I are trying
阻止一场严重的事件
to stop something very bad from happening.
你怎么想
So what do you think?
■
手机摄像头  激活
你应该会想知道
西23街3109号
3109 west 23rd street.
看来我接下来得去这儿了
Looks like that's where I'm headed next.
为什么
Why?
你到了才会知道
You'll find out when you get there.
感谢你的角色扮演
Thanks for playing.
你的临别礼物
Now here's your lovely parting gift.
D区右边第二张桌子
At the second lunch table on the left in cell block D,
坐着一位体重270多斤的[印第安]契卡索人名叫阿诺德
sit across from a 300-pound Chickasaw named Arnold.
他跟你一样酷爱恐龙
He loves dinosaurs as much as you do.
告诉他这点  他就会一直保护你
Tell him that, and he'll have your back forever.
他在这儿
There he is!
警察  警察  别动
Police! Police! Don't move!
不许动
Stay right where you are.
举起手来
Put your hands in the air.
香槟市
纽约
这次要我找谁呢
So whom am I looking for this time?
有权有势的首席执行官
Powerful CEO?
雇佣黑客
A rogue hacker?
伪装成快递员的杀手
A hit man posing as a delivery guy?
有意思
Fascinating.
你好啊  赛勒斯
Hello, Cyrus.
我要带你去吃早餐
I'm supposed to take you to breakfast.
只要三明治吗
Just a pb&j, huh?
确定不想来点鸡蛋吗
You sure you wouldn't rather have some eggs?
免了  谢了  这算我的晚餐了
No, thanks. This is dinner for me.
上夜班必须得保持规律
Working nights is all about routine.
得让自己的身体准备好
Gotta trick your body into going to sleep
在全世界醒来时入睡
when the rest of the world is waking up.
每天都是同样的食物  同样的地点
Same meal, same place every day,
否则我就别想合眼
or I don't sleep a wink.
不过谢谢你这顿饭
But I do appreciate the meal
和热可可
and the hot cocoa.
一般人家会问很多问题
Normally people ask more questions.
-比如呢  -"你是谁"啊
- Such as? - "Who are you?"
"你想我怎么样"啊
"What do you want with me?"
"这到底是怎么回事"啊
"What the hell's going on?"
[西班牙语]
Que sera, sera.
该来的  自然会来
Whatever will be, will be.
我以前不明白
Took me a long time to see it,
凡事都是命中注定  天意安排
but there's an order to things, a plan.
所发生的一切都是注定的
And everything that happens is part of it,
包括你
including you.
不过要是你乐意
But if it makes you feel any better,
"这到底是怎么回事"
What the hell is going on?
我的老大让我跟你谈谈
My boss wanted me to talk to you.
那就是说你我应该
Which means you and I are supposed
一起合作某件事
to do something together,
很重要的事
Something important.
你这工作听着都古怪
Sounds like you got a weird job.
你老大让我干啥
What's your boss want us to do?
她不说
She won't say.
她比较希望我自己弄清楚
She likes it better when I figure it out myself.
你这老大听着都古怪
Sounds like you have a weird boss.
现在我得去公园走走了  风雨无阻
Well, now I go to the park for a walk, rain or shine.
新鲜空气能帮我入眠
Fresh air helps me have good dreams.
你乐意的话  欢迎陪我
You're more than welcome to join if you like.
这么偷偷接近我可不明智啊  哈罗德
You should know better than to try to sneak up on me, Harold.
你是来欢迎我重回纽约吗
Did you come to welcome me back to New York?
其实  我们是为威尔斯先生而来
Actually, we're here for Mr. Wells.
他的号码早上7:04跳了出来
His number came 7:04 this morning.
你那无所不能的机器
Your multifaceted machine
真是神秘莫测啊  是吧
sure does work in mysterious ways, doesn't she?
这次倒不太难测
In this case perhaps not that mysterious.
里瑟先生和肖女士进入他工作的
When Mr. Reese and Ms. Shaw accessed the security system
那栋大楼的安保系统后
in the building where he works,
发现你接近了他
they found you approaching him
正好在早上7:04
at precisely 7:04 a.m.
我初步查看了他的网络数据资料
I've prepared a preliminary study of his digital footprint,
据我判断
and in my estimation
赛勒斯・威尔斯生活中最危险的就是你了
the most dangerous thing in Cyrus Wells's life is you.
不管你的计划如何  格罗夫斯女士
Whatever your plan is, Ms. Groves,
我相信你会害他送命
I believe you're gonna get him killed.
疑犯追踪
第三季第十七集
别紧张  哈罗德
Relax, Harold.
不会有人送命的
Nobody's getting anybody killed.
赛勒斯跟我在一起非常安全
Cyrus is perfectly safe with me.
既然机器把他的号码发给我们
If the machine sent us his number,
那可能意味着是你把威尔斯先生置于危险之中了
it may mean that you are placing Mr. Wells at risk.
或者意味着我来保护他了
Or it could mean I'm here to protect him.
坦白说  哈罗德  要跟上
Honestly, Harold, keeping up with everything
机器对我说的每一句话可不容易
the machine whispers in my ear can be tricky,
特别是现在我还废了一只耳朵
especially now that I'm down to one.
天呐
Oh, my.
你没听说过我跟主控者的聊天吗
Did you not hear about my chat with Control?
她很有趣
She's fun...
跟个没必要的镫骨切除术一样
in an unnecessary stapedectomy kind of way.
我还挺怀念立体声音乐
but I do miss music in stereo.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
机器给了我一份工作
The machine offered me a job.
她可没说这会很容易
She never said it would be easy.
那到底是什么工作呢
And what job is that exactly?
当然是拯救世界
Trying to save the world, of course.
阻止第二台机器的出现
By preventing the emergence of a second machine.
"撒马利亚人"
Samaritan.
基因编程  目标明确  几近完成
Genetically programmed, fully targetable, and nearly complete.
"撒马利亚人"严重威胁到了我们的机器  哈罗德
Samaritan presents a serious threat to our machine, Harold.
而德西玛想要把它激活
and Decima's trying to bring it to life.
难道你想看到两位上帝开战
Do you really want to see what it looks like
是何等场面吗
when two Gods go to war?
或许你更应该担心的是
Maybe you should be more worried
"撒马利亚人"上线之后会造成什么后果
about what happens when Samaritan comes online
而不是担心一位清洁工
than about what happens to some janitor.
你对那位清洁工了解多少  格罗夫斯女士
How much do you know about this janitor, Ms. Groves?
他对于形而上学决定论的看法挺有意思
He's got some interesting ideas about metaphysical determinism,
我觉得他是[德国女导演]多丽丝・戴的粉丝
and I think he's a Doris Day fan.
你知道他有福德姆学院金融学硕士学位吗
Do you know that he has an MBA in finance from Fordham?
你知道他在35岁时已经是千万富翁了吗
Do you know he was a multimillionaire by the age of 35?
你知道他2009年之后就不在华尔街上班了吗
Do you know he hasn't worked on Wall Street since 2009?
你根本不关心为什么吧
Would you even care to know why?
也许你应该让机器
Perhaps you should ask the machine
多告诉你一点塞勒斯・威尔斯的信息
for a bit more information about Cyrus Wells
再对他妄下结论  随意轻视
before you deem him insignificant.
他没事的  我保证
He'll be fine, I promise.
我知道听起来都古怪
I know it seems weird,
但我现在是好人了噢  哈罗德
but I'm one of the good guys now, Harold.
起效迅速
功效强大
蓝色雷管
纯天然引爆男性雄风
从下数第三  从右数第十五  在你身后
Third from the bottom, 15th on the right, behind you.
根不肯撒手
Root wouldn't take "Go" for an answer?
恐怕是不肯
No, I'm afraid not.
似乎她觉得自己一切尽在掌握
Seems that she thinks she has the situation well in hand.
格罗夫斯女士向来不在乎
Ms. Groves has never been particularly concerned
间接伤害
about collateral damage,
这样塞勒斯・威尔斯就要成牺牲品了
which may be precisely what Cyrus Wells is about to become.
搞清楚之前  盯紧他们
Watch over them until we can figure out what's going on.
与此同时  我要弄明白
In the meantime, I'll try to determine
这个东西是什么意思
what message this is meant to convey.
起效迅速
功效强大
蓝色雷管
纯天然引爆男性雄风
我看挺明白的  芬奇
Seems pretty clear to me, Finch.
我觉得她喜欢你  哈罗德
I think she likes you, Harold.
我不想表现失礼之类的
So I don't want to be rude or anything,
不过
but, yeah,
谢谢你请我喝热可可
look, thank you for the hot cocoa,
也谢谢你陪我走回家
and it was nice of you to walk me home.
不过你现在搞的这些个东西没有
But whatever it is you're doing right now is not--
很有必要  相信我
Necessary. Trust me.
我听说你没吃早餐
I heard you skipped breakfast.
你和你的野蛮原始人同伴
And you and your australopithecine coworker
今天可以休息了
can just take the day off.
没有安全保障  我也一直没事
I've been doing just fine without a safety net.
你现在没被关在笼子里  完全是因为我
Look, the only reason you're not stuck in a cage right now is me.
别让我脸上无光
Don't make me look bad.
绝不可能  你永远光彩照人啊
I couldn't make you look bad if I tried.
你该收拾洗漱用品了
You should start packing your toiletries.
不不不  好吗
No, no, no, okay?
真的  不
Seriously, no.
我今晚还要工作
I have to work again tonight.
我要睡觉  所以你该离开了
I need to sleep, so it's time for you to leave.
实际上  我们俩都该离开了
Actually, it's time for us both to leave.
事情会越来越有趣
Things are about to get interesting.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
是不是跟我以前的工作有关
Is this about what happened at my old job?
以前发生了什么
What did happen?
不关你事  给我
None of your business. Give me that.
他们是谁  塞勒斯
Who are these people, Cyrus?
他们的名字  可能很重要
Their names. It could be important.
不重要  你该走了
It's not. You have to go.
他们受到伤害了吗  你受到伤害了吗
Did they get hurt? Did you get hurt?
我得知道发生了什么
I-I need to know what happened.
芬奇  我看到了一个狙击手
Finch, I've got eyes on a sniper.
我可能有枪手的线索了
And I might have a lead on who's doing the shooting.
起效迅速
功效强大
纯天然引爆男性雄风
蓝色雷管
起效迅速
功效强大
纯天然引爆男性雄风
蓝色雷管
格罗夫斯女士发给我的小广告
The solicitation Ms. Groves gave me
看上去像是垃圾邮件
is visually identical to an image commonly sent out as spam.
但是图像中隐藏了数字化信息
but digitally someone has hidden a message inside the image.
起效迅速
功效强大
纯天然引爆男性雄风
蓝色雷管
使用了运动密钥加密法
It's encrypted with a running key cipher.
但我无法解码  除非
But I can't decode it without--
在你身后  从下数第三  从右数第十五
"behind you, third from the bottom, 15th from the right."
德・托克维尔
De Tocqueville.
19世纪法国自由主义民主思想代表人物
我知道我们对付的是谁了
I believe I know who we're dealing with.
"时刻警惕"
Vigilance.
我们去追她
We'll take her.
你们四个去找目标
You four get the target.
又来了
It's happening again.
你能不能等会儿再发作
Do you think you could do that later?
我们现在得走了
Cause we should probably go.
别别别  求你了
No, no, no. Please.
枪让我非常紧张
Guns make me very, very nervous.
外面有一名狙击手
We've got a sniper outside
还有四名全副武装的隐私恐怖份子
and four heavily-armed privacy terrorists
正从北边楼梯间上来
coming up the north stairwell.
有把枪就好了  可是
So a gun would be nice, but...
你真是面面俱到
you think of everything.
催泪瓦斯  憋住气
Tear gas. Hold your breath.
等等  狙击手怎么办
Wait. What about the sniper?
相信我
Trust me.
想试试谁的枪法更好吗
Wanna see who's got better aim?
看到目标了
Got eyes on the target.
我们的威胁恐怕不止"时刻警惕"了  里瑟先生
I'm afraid Vigilance may not be our only threat, Mr. Reese.
我破译了那个垃圾邮件
I decrypted their spam message,
看来"时刻警惕"要抓威尔斯先生是因为
and it seems that Vigilance is only targeting Mr. Wells
他的名字出现在了他们截获的一封密件上
because his name came up in a secret communique they intercepted
来自德西玛公司
from Decima.
看来根不是我们最大的麻烦了
I don't think Root's our biggest problem anymore.
那些家伙是什么人
Who are those guys?
告诉过你事情会越来越有趣
I told you things were gonna get interesting.
看到目标了  先生  现在动手
The target's in sight, sir. We're moving in.
我们不该跑吗
Shouldn't we run?
我听不清老大的话了
I can't hear my boss.
给你二十块
Here's $20.
为什么停下来
Why are we stopping?
因为有更多人从那四个人的方向来了
Because there are more where those four came from.
只有这样能让你脱身
And this is the quickest way to get you out of here
还不用开枪
without shooting someone.
他们铐你时
Keep your shoulders relaxed
肩膀要放松
when they put the handcuffs on.
你
You!
举起手来
Hands in the air.
什么
What?
举起手来
Hands in the air.
塞勒斯安全了  芬奇
Cyrus is safe, Finch.
但我们得让弗斯科保护好他
But we'll need Fusco's help to keep it that way.
格罗夫斯女士呢
And Ms. Groves?
不见了
Gone.
德西玛派来的人也不见了
So are the boys from Decima.
知道塞勒斯到底干了什么
Do we have any idea what Cyrus did
才会惹到德西玛和"时刻警惕"了吗
to piss off both them and Vigilance?
就目前情况来看  一无所知
As far as I can tell, nothing.
不过现在  我开始怀疑比起旧工作
But whatever's going on, I'm starting to suspect
他的新工作与此事牵连更多
that it has more to do with his new job than his old one.
我黑进了塞勒斯做清洁服务的
I hacked the computer system
那家公司的电脑系统
at the janitorial service that employs Cyrus
发现他们最近对他做了背景调查
and discovered they recently ran a background check on him.
为什么
Why?
什么样的清洁工需要背景调查
What kind of janitor needs a background check?
值得一查
Something to look into
待我们联系上肖女士
when we reconnect with Ms. Shaw.
枪战开始时我便失去了她的信号
I lost her signal when the shooting started.
她说她看到了狙击手
She said she saw a sniper.
但我在这儿没看到她
But I don't see any sign of her here.
肖和塞勒斯一比
Between Shaw and Cyrus,
谁更需要帮助不言而喻
I think I know who needs our help more.
那我们只得相信肖女士的自救能力了
Then I'm afraid we'll have to trust Ms. Shaw to take care of herself.
■
搜寻执行人
肖  萨姆恩
来源  声纹确认
地点:
纽约州纽约哈德森街705E三楼
既然你一时半会死不了  那我们来聊聊
Now that you're not gonna die, we can have a little chat.
你需要去医院
So you need a hospital,
我需要知道为何大家都追杀那位清洁工
and I need to know why everyone's after the janitor.
你欠我个狙击手
You owe me a sniper.
科利尔  对吗
This is Collier, right?
至少是你的化名
Or at least that's your alias?
我不知道你的名字
Can't say I know yours.
那我就叫你机会目标好了
So I'll just call you a target of opportunity.
"时刻警惕"到这来是为了审问塞勒斯・威尔斯
Vigilance came here to interrogate Cyrus Wells,
但现在却为你而来
but now we're here for you.
从你打斗的招式可以看出
See, based on the way you fight,
你曾是一名为美利坚效忠的
I think you were a clandestine operative
秘密行动成员
for the good old U.S. Of A.
但从你保护的人来看
But based on the people you protect,
现在应该不是了
I think you're not anymore.
我估计是因为他们背叛了你
And I'm guessing it's because they betrayed you.
你们是准备开枪打死我
Are you guys gonna shoot again
还是说话说死我
or just talk me to death?
实际上我更想知道你要说什么
Actually I'm more interested in what you have to say.
所以我自行封住了出口
So I've taken the liberty of sealing off the exits.
作为交换  我需要你告诉我
Now in exchange for everything you know
你所知道关于"撒马利亚人"的一切
about the Samaritan system
还有他的建造者们
and the people that are trying to build it,
我准备给你提供
I'm prepared to offer you something
绝无仅有的
that no one else can--
向出卖了你的政府复仇
Revenge on the government that betrayed you.
如果我拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
用本杰明・富兰克林的话说
In the words of Benjamin Franklin,
不团结  则死亡
join or die.
■
搜寻执行人
肖  萨姆恩
最后出现地点
纽约州纽约哈德森街705E三楼
威胁人数                                11
你见到威尔斯先生了吗  警探
Have you secured Mr. Wells, Detective?
他在我这儿
Yeah, I got him.
我还在搞起诉撤销
And I'm clearing up the charges too.
千万别跟我客气
You're welcome very much.
言语不足以表达
A phrase which now makes my thanks
我的感激之情  警探
seem less than sincere, Detective.
我把你和里瑟先生会合点的GPS坐标发给你
I'm sending you GPS coordinates for a rendezvous with Mr. Reese,
他会负责保护威尔斯先生
who will henceforth protect Mr. Wells.
好
All right.
好了  伙计  我带你离开这儿
Okay, pal, let's get you out of here.
走吧  这边
Come on, this way.
你又忘了从储蓄账号把钱转出来了  莱奈尔
You forgot to transfer from savings again, Lionel.
你的租金支票要被退回了
Your rent check's gonna bounce.
塞勒斯
Hi, Cyrus.
想得美  飞越疯人院的
Nice try, Cuckoo's Nest.
我绝不会让你带走他的
There's no way I'm letting him leave here with you.
我理解
I understand.
但有些事你不知道
But there are things you don't know.
首先  你不知道
For starters, you don't know
现在想要塞勒斯死的不是一个
that Cyrus is currently wanted by not one,
而是两个极端危险的组织
but two very dangerous organizations.
其次  你不知道
And you have no idea
目前有27个人正在赶往这里的途中
that there are currently 27 people en route to this location,
离我们最近的那人带了两把未登记枪支
the closest of whom is carrying two concealed firearms
外加一柄手推短剑
and a push dagger
他上个月才用它在迪拜杀了三个人
he used to kill three people in Dubai last month--
其中之一只是为了好玩
one of them just for fun.
我才不管你的脑容量多大
I don't care how big your brain is.
谁都别想从我手里把人带走
Nobody's taking this guy from me
除非有联邦逮捕令  知道不
without a big fat federal warrant, you got that?
我上个月进了联调局
Joined the bureau last month
为了获得[俄克拉荷马]塔尔萨一家核电站的权限
to get access to a nuclear plant in Tulsa.
说来话长
Long story.
有什么问题吗  弗斯科
Is there a problem here, Fusco?
没有  警长
No captain.
没问题
There's no problem.
这儿有后门吗
Is there a back way out of here?
有  在
Yeah, it's, uh--
我没问你
I wasn't asking you.
你让她怎么了
You let her what?
她有逮捕令  真的逮捕令
She had a warrant-- a real one.
你能指望我说什么
What was I supposed to say?
"抱歉  老大
"Sorry, boss,
金探员实际上是个超能力怪物
Agent King is actually a superpowered nutball.
不信问我哥们儿啊  那位都市传奇"
Just ask my buddy, the Urban Legend."
别紧张  约翰
Relax, John.
有点信心啊
Have a little faith.
你大错特错了
You're making a mistake.
塞勒斯跟我在一起更安全
Cyrus is safer with me.
你不是真的相信吧
You don't really believe that, do you?
你和哈罗德根本没找到
Have you and Harold even figured out
德西玛追杀他的原因吧
why Decima is after him yet?
你所拥有的能力
That power you have?
我也拥有过
I've had it too.
我知道一切答案
I know just what it's like to have
都在耳朵里回响是什么感觉
all those answers buzzing in your ear.
但最终  你仍得做出选择
But at the end of the day, you still make choices.
如果你现在的选择害死了塞勒斯
And if the choice you're making now gets Cyrus killed
无论发生什么
Whatever happens,
我都能及时拯救他
I'll be there to save him,
就像我当初及时拯救你一样
just like I was there to save you.
我们一起经历那么多了  约翰
After everything we've been through together, John,
你真该相信我
you really should trust me.
你确定这里安全吗
Are you sure it's safe here?
无论在哪儿我都能保护你
I can protect you anywhere.
我觉得这里能让你放松点
I thought this place might help you relax.
抱歉让你错过了睡觉时间
Sorry I've kept you up past your bedtime.
没关系
Yeah, that's all right.
老实说  反正我的睡眠也不怎么好
To tell the truth, I don't sleep very well anyway.
说到那个
Yeah, about that--
我还是想知道发生了什么事
I'd still like to know what happened.
你老大似乎无所不知
Your boss seems to know everything.
为什么不问她
Why don't you ask her?
我问了
I did.
她不告诉我
She won't tell me.
拜托  塞勒斯  这些人是谁
Please, Cyrus, who are these people?
萨拉・林德和亚历克斯・赖斯
Sarah Lind and Alex Rice--
我大学最好的朋友
my best friends from college.
毕业后
After graduation,
他们创办了一家小型金融服务公司
they started a small financial services firm
还带我入伙帮他们经营
and brought me on to help 'em run it.
当所有人都在房地产市场下大赌注时
When everybody was betting big on the housing market,
我们稳扎稳打
we played it safe.
所以金融危机时
So when the crash came,
我们一跃而起  成功登顶
we went from a small start-up to a major player.
但遭人嫉妒了
But somebody was jealous.
一天有个人走进我们的办公室
'Cause one day a guy walked into our office
开始扫射
and started shooting.
亚历克斯和萨拉被杀
Alex and Sarah were killed.
还有五人都中枪  包括我
Five others were shot, including me.
枪手身份未知
The gunman was never identified.
枪击案发生在哪天
And when was this, exactly?
2009年4月4日
April 4, 2009.
-我很抱歉  -不必
- I'm sorry. - Don't be.
在重症监护室里呆了十周
Ten weeks in I.C.U.
让人认真反思
makes you take a long, hard look at things.
我才发现自己浪费了三十年时间
I realized I had wasted the first 30 years of my life
光想着赚钱
putting zeros on my bank account.
所以我把所有钱捐给了慈善机构
So I gave all my money away to charity.
现在我每晚起床
Now I get up every night
去把大楼打扫干净
and keep that building spic and span.
谁不喜欢干净地板呢
'cause who doesn't like clean floors?
[西语]该来的  自然会来
Que sera, sera.
那天发生的事是命中注定
What happened that day was part of a plan.
不不  那个
No. No, what--
那件事  相信我
Whatever this was, believe me,
绝对不是什么命运安排
it was not part of some grand cosmic plan.
我们得走了
We need to go.
他们快来了
They're almost here.
我们到了您指示的位置  先生
We're at the coordinates you sent, sir.
但没有发现目标
But we can't get a visual on the targets.
你们会发现的
You will.
采用反制措施
Deploy the countermeasure.
■
模拟互动界面:  活动中
意外干扰出现
模拟互动界面:  掉线
信号断开
能听到我吗
Can you hear me?
错误
连接断开
-现在怎么办  -逃
- What do we do now? - Run.
-带上车  -塞勒斯
- Get in the car! - Cyrus!
接你的电话吧
I guess you better answer that.
■
搜寻执行人
肖  萨姆恩
最后出现地点
纽约州纽约哈德森街705E三楼
威胁人数                                 10
距离出口                                     米
放下武器
Drop the weapon!
马上放下
Drop it now!
我不想杀爱国人士
I don't like killing patriots,
所以我再给你一次机会
so I'm gonna give you one more chance.
真有趣  我正想说这句
That's funny, I was gonna say the same thing to you.
看吧  我知道我们有共鸣
See, I knew we had something in common--
似乎有很多共鸣
Many things, I suspect.
不是只有你被政府背叛
You're not the only one the government has betrayed.
所以我想要你帮我
And that's why I want your help.
美国正在消亡
See, America's dying.
每个人都明白
And everybody knows it.
并不只是隐私问题  更是原则问题
It's not just about privacy, it's about principle.
我们国家用无人机暗杀民众
Our nation is assassinating people with drones,
非法监禁民众
holding them without due process,
对了  还有监视本国人民
and, yes, spying on its own people
毫无依据  毫无限制
without cause or limits
悍然违宪
and in direct violation of our constitution.
但我们计划加以制止
But we have a plan to stop it.
你加入我们
And if you join us,
你不仅能复仇
you will not only have your revenge,
还能写下美国历史的新篇章
but you will help write a new chapter in American history.
你说得都没错
You're right about all of it.
我的确曾为政府工作
I did work for the government,
我也想要复仇
and I do want revenge.
但那份工作只教会了我一件事
But if that work taught me anything,
达成目标的方式
it's that how you do
和目标本身一样重要
matters as much as what you do.
据此衡量  你们都是恐怖分子
And by that metric, you're all just terrorists.
我专杀恐怖分子
And I kill terrorists.
我在离公园三里外跟丢德西玛了
I lost Decima's trail about a mile from the park.
有没有其他方法找到赛勒斯
Do we have any other way to find Cyrus?
现在没有
Not at the moment.
但我知道了为什么德西玛想抓他
But I may have discovered why Decima wants him.
只有15人能进入这层楼: 塞勒斯・威尔斯
我发现了"时刻警惕"
I've located the original communique
从德西玛那拦截的原始信息
that Vigilance intercepted from Decima,
引发了这堆事那条信息
The message that started all of this.
上边显示塞勒斯是15名有视网膜进入权限的人之一
It lists Cyrus as 1 of 15 people with retinal access.
视网膜扫描仪吗
As in retinal scanner?
那栋楼里有扇门
So somewhere out there is a door,
塞勒斯・威尔斯的眼睛就是钥匙
and Cyrus Wells' eye is the key.
我想我知道那扇门在哪里
I believe I might know where that door is.
经过背景调查
After passing his background check at work,
塞勒斯是唯一
Cyrus became the only custodian
能进入19层的保洁员
allowed on the 19th floor.
19楼有什么
What's on the 19th floor?
麦斯威尔有限公司
A company called "Maxwell limited."
我现在掌握的信息只有
All I know about them so far is that
这家公司定时运送液态氦气
they take regular deliveries of liquid helium.
我猜不是用来充气球的
I'm guessing they're not blowing up balloons.
麦斯威尔公司可能运送它去冷却
Maxwell could be using it to cool
生物医学反应堆
anything from biomedical reactors to--
世界上最快的电脑
The fastest computer ever built.
麦斯威尔是国安局实验室的幌子
Maxwell's the corporate cover for an NSA lab.
两天前
And two days ago,
实验室内部人员发送了这个
somebody working in that lab sent this.
你应该会想知道
天啊
Oh, my.
芬奇  怎么了
Okay, Finch, what am I missing here?
这是电脑科学家给同行写的纸条
It's a note from one computer scientist to another,
上面写着超导处理器的规格
detailing the specifications of a superconducting processor,
比现行处理器要快上三倍
three times faster than anything now available.
由于政府不肯将其卖给德西玛
And since the government's not about to sell it to them,
他们打算利用塞勒斯去偷
Decima plans to use Cyrus to steal it.
最初撒马利亚人系统崩溃  是因为当时
The original Samaritan crashed because a chip
运算速度足够快的芯片还没有制造出来
fast enough to run it hadn't been built yet.
两天前  有人制造出来了
Two days ago, somebody built it.
德西玛有了软件
Decima has the software.
现在  他们想要硬件
Now they want the hardware.
现在  我更担心的是塞勒斯
Right now, I'm more worried about Cyrus.
他一旦开了门
As soon as he opens that door,
德西玛就会杀了他
Decima's gonna kill him.
我想你要去找里瑟先生
I suppose you'll be joining Mr. Reese.
还不行
Not just yet.
德西玛之前断开了我和机器的连接
Decima's severed my link to the machine.
一小会儿  但她不喜欢那样
Temporarily, but she didn't like that.
所以
So...
她要你把这些接进这个里
she wants you to patch these into this.
上次你对我们该帮不帮
The last time you didn't help us when you should have,
有人送了命
people died.
装置装好后
And once this device is installed,
你会救哪个
which will you save:
芯片  还是塞勒斯・威尔斯
The chip or Cyrus Wells?
是你害他身陷危险
Since it was you who put him in danger.
好吧  哈罗德
Fine, Harold.
都是我的错
It's all my fault--
都是我跟机器的错  满意了吧
Mine and the machine's. Happy?
一点也不  但我的确相信
Far from it, but I do believe
应该从中吸取教训  戒狂戒傲
that there's a lesson here about hubris.
最了解"狂傲"
If anyone would know about hubris,
莫过于造出上帝的人
it would be the man who built God.
她很担心你  哈罗德
She's worried about you, Harold.
我们都很担心你
We both are.
过去三个月里  你平均每晚
The past three months, you've slept an average
只睡了四个小时
of four hours per night.
我的事与你无关  格罗夫斯女士
My problems are no concern of yours, Ms. Groves.
如果拿出这十分之一的劲头
Perhaps if you had 1/10 as much interest
关心塞勒斯  他现在可能就不会
in Cyrus's welfare, he might not be about--
按你自己的定义
By your own definition,
塞勒斯是无关号码
Cyrus is irrelevant.
每个人都会与某些人相关
Everyone is relevant to someone.
S01E22开头
那个人在他生命中的每一天
That man has spent every day of his life
都相信有所谓的天意安排
believing that there is actually some sort of higher plan.
这就是人类的问题
That's the problem with humans--
他们总是待在原地  期望着
They just sit around, hoping that
有人来解决一切
someone will fix things.
但是没人会  没人在乎
But no one will. No one cares.
宇宙无穷无尽
The universe is infinite
混乱  冷酷
and chaotic and cold.
从来就没有天意安排
And there has never been a plan.
直到现在
At least not till now.
你想知道他们死那天的安排吗
You wanna know what the plan was the day they died?
那天的安排是有人想赚1500万
The plan was for someone to make $15 million.
一家大银行的高管要他们死
An executive at a big bank wanted them dead,
所以他花钱雇了一个有能力
so he wired the money to someone with the skills,
有资源  又毫无道德感的人去安排
resources, and moral depravity to make that happen.
那个人就是我
And that someone was me.
好笑的是
And the punch line
你的机器一直要我去救塞勒斯
is that your machine keeps telling me to save Cyrus.
你到底把它毁得有多惨
How badly did you have to break it
才能让它如此在乎生命
to make it care about people so much?
这并没有毁它  它以此存在
That didn't break it. It's what made it work.
我教会了机器生命的重要
It was only after I taught the machine that people mattered,
它才能够帮助人类
that it could begin to be able to help them.
我也想如此对你
I'd like to do the same thing for you,
请允许我
if you'd let me.
"撒马利亚人"上线三十分钟内
In the first 30 minutes after Samaritan comes online,
很多人会送命
a lot of people are gonna be killed.
首当其中的四个人
But they're gonna start with four:
你  我  你的宠物  和肖
You, me, your helper monkey, and Shaw.
届时任何人
And there won't be a damn thing anyone,
包括你的机器  都无能为力
including your machine, can do to stop it.
你觉得我不在乎生命  哈罗德
You think I don't care about people, Harold?
我做了这么多  都是为了救你
I'm doing all of this to save you.
抱歉  医生
Sorry, doctor.
我没时间预约
I didn't have time to make an appointment.
但我知道你会为我破例
But I know you'll make an exception for me.
是吗
Really?
你是怎么知道的
And how do you know that?
正如我知道我可以一枪打穿你的手
The same way I know I can put a bullet through your hand
让你来不及拨打911报警
before you can dial 911.
正如我知道你是四百公里内最好的耳鼻喉科医生
The same way I know you're the best otolaryngologist in 250 miles.
好吧  你想要什么  药吗
Okay, uh, what do you want? Drugs?
不
Not really.
不过来点[麻醉剂]利多卡因倒是不错
Although a little lidocaine would be nice.
上次的手术我没用到
I didn't get any the last time.
有人弄坏了我的耳朵
You see, somebody broke my ear.
你得帮我修好它
And you're gonna fix it.
大楼保安搞定了
Building security has been neutralized.
我们可以去拿芯片了
We're ready to take the chip.
那就行动吧
Then let's begin, shall we?
非常好
Very good.
现在可以处理掉他了
You may dispose of him now.
等等  你们  不  放开我
Wait. What are you-- no, let me go!
请坐  恢复时间最少三周
Please. The minimum healing time is three weeks before--
很遗憾  我现在就要工作
Unfortunately, I'm on a bit of a schedule.
不需要
And I won't be needing that.
好  我启动
Okay, I'm turning it on.
■
模拟互动界面:  活动中
固件升级
你会听到一系列音调
Now you're going to hear a series of tones.
我听到了
I can hear you.
我还没开始
I didn't start yet.
我没跟你说话
I wasn't talking to you.
我们进入实验室了
We're in the lab.
拿走所有的研究资料  清空电脑
Take all the research, wipe the computers,
找出芯片
and locate the chip.
欲速则不达
Haste makes waste.
实验室被冷却到接近绝对零度
The chamber is cooled to within a few degrees of absolute zero.
零下268摄氏度
现在打开你们都会送命
Opening now would kill you all.
更重要的是会伤到芯片
And more importantly damage the chip.
仔细听好升温步骤
Listen closely to the warm-up protocol
严格照我说的做
and do exactly as I say.
不不  求你们了  不要
No, no, please, don't.
安静  很快就会结束
Settle down. It'll all be over soon.
漂白剂多着呢
We got plenty of bleach.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no.
天意安排不会如此
This is not the plan.
天意安排不该如此
This can't be the plan.
上帝啊
Oh, God!
你跟他说什么了
What did you say to him?
战斗模式
锁定  启动
截击时间
她可真难缠
She is persistent.
反制措施
Countermeasures.
战斗模式
耳蜗植入 启动
手机  信号丢失
无线  信号丢失
蓝牙  信号丢失
次声
重新连接
零下40摄氏度
233 Kelvin.
实验室安全了
The chamber is now safe.
拿了芯片走
Get the chip and go.
弗斯科
Fusco.
我要去塞勒斯那边
I'm gonna try to get to Cyrus.
掩护我
Be ready to cover me.
他只会再次逃走
He'll just run away again.
他不喜欢枪
He doesn't like guns.
你当机器会帮你躲子弹吗
You think the machine's gonna help you dodge bullets?
不
No.
没事的  我来了
It's okay. I'm coming to you.
塞勒斯  想离开这儿吗
Cyrus, wanna get out of here?
麦斯威尔芯片到手了  先生
The Maxwell chip is in custody, sir.
我们已清除了周边
We've cleared the perimeter.
这里的工作完成
Then our work here is done.
麻烦清理干净
Do tidy up, please.
塞勒斯安全了  芬奇
Cyrus is safe, Finch,
但德西玛带着芯片跑了
but Decima got away with the chip.
那可能不是我们的唯一损失
That may not be our only loss.
我仍旧没有肖女士
I still haven't heard from Ms.--
你们干嘛去了
What happened to you guys?
错过好戏了
You missed all the fun.
他们在说什么
What are they saying?
我知道你没法再黑她了
I know you can't bluejack her anymore.
但你以为我们会相信你没有窃听那阳台吗
But do you expect us to believe you didn't bug that balcony?
我觉得应该给他们留点隐私
I suppose I thought they deserved some privacy.
看来是时候离开了
Looks like it's time to go.
我希望你不介意开启一段新生活
I hope you don't mind starting a new life.
早有此意
I was about due for one.
再说  这是天意注定
Besides, it's all part of the plan.
保持干燥
Keep 'em dry.
每72小时更换一次敷料
Change the dressings every 72 hours.
我好喜欢你扮医生呢
I love it when you play doctor.
这只是巧合吗
Was it just a coincidence--
塞勒斯和我
Cyrus and me?
还是机器想表达什么
Or was the machine trying to make some sort of point?
那你要去问机器了
You'd have to ask the machine.
我问了
I did.
她不说
She's not telling.
你告诉威尔斯先生
Did you inform Mr. Wells
你在他过去所扮演的角色了吗
about your role in his past?
我想说
I wanted to.
但那只是为了解脱我
But that would've been for me.
塞勒斯所信仰的
What Cyrus believes, it--
帮助了他
it helps him.
我又凭什么说他是错的
And who am I to say he's wrong?
她要我二十分钟内登上飞往巴拉圭的飞机
She wants me on a plane to Paraguay in 20 minutes.
关于那个
About that--
关于"撒马利亚人"所能构成的威胁  你说得没错
You're not wrong about the threat Samaritan poses.
虽然你我在某些问题上颇有分歧
And though you and I may not see eye to eye on some things,
但也许我们应该多点儿合作
perhaps we should collaborate a bit more.
为此
Toward that end--
弗斯科警探来接我
Detective Fusco is here to take me
去该去的地方了
where I need to go.
你好啊  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
飞越疯人院的  打着表呢
Cuckoo's Nest, the meter's running.
你的烟雾警报器将在凌晨2:41响起
Your smoke alarm's gonna start beeping at 2:41 a.m.
状态  正在进化
程序  撒马利亚人
威胁执行人
化名  里瑟  约翰
代号  主控者
威胁主体
姓名  马丁内斯  玛丽亚
威胁执行人
化名  科利尔  彼得
状态  正在进化
程序  撒马利亚人
重大灾难事件
威胁执行人
姓名  弗斯科  莱奈尔
化名  肖  萨姆恩
威胁管理员  死亡可能性
威胁主体
化名  赫什  罗伯特